Finding Aid for the Renée Levine Packer Papers, 1963-circa 2015
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Book, interview, and research files for Gay Guerrilla: Julius Eastman and His Music, circa 2000-2015, XII.; Folder572-607
  - Interview and other recordings, 1973-2009, XII.B; Item 609-636
    - Cage, John: Songbooks I, II (excerpt), 1973-12-08, 1 CD (Box 28, Item 636)
Feldman, Morton Essays. Kerpen: Beginner Press, ©1985.
Freeman, Betty Music people: the photographic works of Betty Freeman. [Japan]: [publisher not identified], [1989?]
Freeman, Betty. Music people and others: 99 photographs from the contemporary music world. Salzburg [Germany]; Festival Press, ©1996.
Freeman, Betty. Music people and others. Milano: Mazzotta, ©1987.
Freeman, Betty. Music people and others. [Berlin?]: [publisher not identified], [1990?]
Freeman, Betty. Betty Freeman: music people: 75 Porträts: Deutsche Oper Berlin. Zürich; Festival Press, ©1998.
Gann, Kyle. No such thing as silence: John Cage's 4'33". New Haven [Conn.]: Yale University Press, ©2010.
Gann, Kyle. Music downtown: writings from the Village voice. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©2006.
Gardner, Howard Creating minds: an anatomy of creativity seen through the lives of Freud, Einstein, Picasso, Stravinsky, Eliot, Graham, and Gandhi. New York: BasicBooks, ©1993.
Garland, Peter Americas: essays on American music and culture, 1973-80. Santa Fe: Soundings Press, 1982.
Gillies, Malcolm. Portrait of Percy Grainger. Rochester, NY: University of Rochester Press, 2002.
Gold, Arthur. Misia: the life of Misia Sert. New York: Morrow Quill Paperbacks, 1981, ©1980.
Grant, Kerry S. The rainbow city: celebrating light, color, and architecture at the Pan-American Exposition, Buffalo, 1901. Buffalo, N.Y.: Canisius College Press, [2001]
Griffiths, Paul Modern music: the avant garde since 1945. New York: G. Braziller, 1981.
Hanhardt, John G. The worlds of Nam June Paik. New York: Guggenheim Museum, ©2000.
Horowitz, Joseph Wagner nights: an American history. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©1994.
Howard, John Tasker Modern music: a popular guide to greater musical enjoyment. New York: Mentor, 1957.
Kahan, Sylvia. Music's modern muse: a life of Winnaretta Singer, princesse de Polignac. Rochester, NY: University of Rochester Press, 2003.
Kapp, Julius 200 [i.e. Zweihundert] Jahre Staatsoper in Bildaus Anlass des 200 jährigen Jubiläums der Berliner Staatsoper in Auftrage der Generalintendanz der Preussischen Staatstheater. Berlin, M. Hesse, 1942.
Kapp, Julius 200 [i.e. Zweihundert] Jahre Staatsoper in Bildaus Anlass des 200 jährigen Jubiläums der Berliner Staatsoper in Auftrage der Generalintendanz der Preussischen Staatstheater. Berlin, M. Hesse, 1942.
Katz, Mark Capturing sound: how technology has changed music. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©2004.
Klosty, James. Merce Cunningham. New York, Saturday Review Press [1975]
Kolodin, Irving The Metropolitan opera, 1883-1935 New York, Oxford University Press, 1936.
Lang, Paul Henry Problems of modern music: the Princeton seminar in advanced musical studies. New York: W.W. Norton, 1962, ©1960.
Langer, Susanne K. Philosophy in a new key: a study in the symbolism of reason, rite, and art. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, ©1957.
Levine Packer, Renée Alternative arts organizations in the United States: a report to the Ford Foundation. [New York]: [Ford Foundation], 1988.
Morrison, Jack The maturing of the arts on the American campus: a commentary. Lanham, MD: University Press of America, ©1985.
Nodelman, Sheldon The Rothko Chapel paintings: origins, structure, meaning. Austin: University of Texas Press, c1997.
Nyman, Michael. Experimental music: Cage and beyond. New York: Schirmer Books, 1981, ©1974.
Oja, Carol J. Making music modern: New York in the 1920s. New York: Oxford University Press, 2000.
Patterson, Benjamin. Born in the state of flux/us [Italy]: Alga Marghen, [2011?]
Perloff, Marjorie. The futurist moment: avant-garde, avant guerre, and the language of rupture. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, 1986.
Perone, Karen L. Lukas Foss: a bio-bibliography. New York: Greenwood Press, 1991.
Piekut, Benjamin Experimentalism otherwise: the New York avant-garde and its limits. Berkeley: University of California Press, ©2011.
Pinch, T. J. Analog days: the invention and impact of the Moog synthesizer. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 2002.
Poulenc, Francis Les mamelles de Tiresias: opera-bouffe in two acts and a prologue. Bryn Mawr, PA: Huegel/Theodore Presser Co., ©1954.
Puccini, Giacomo Turandot, drame lyrique en 3 actes and 5 tableaux Milano, G. Ricordi [©1926]
Puccini, Giacomo Turandot: dramma lirico in tre atti e cinque quadri. Milano; G. Ricordi, ©1926.
Ravel, Maurice L'enfant et les sortileges: fantaisie lyrique en deux parties. Bryn Mawr, Pa.: Elkan-Vogel, [19--]
Reich, Steve Writings on music, 1965-2000. Oxford; Oxford University Press, 2002.
Reich, Steve The cave. [London]: Hendon Music; ©1993.
Reich, Steve The cave. [Vienna]: Wiener Festwochen, 1993.
Reisem, Richard O. Classic Buffalo: a heritage of distinguished architecture. Buffalo, NY: Canisius College Press, 1999.
Revill, David The roaring silence: John Cage, a life. New York: Arcade Pub., ©1992.
Rockwell, John All American music: composition in the late twentieth century. New York: Knopf: ©1983.
Schwartz, Elliott Contemporary composers on contemporary music. New York, Holt, Rinehart and Winston [1967]
Shawn, Allen. Arnold Schoenberg's journey. New York: Farrar, Straus and Giroux, 2002.
Smith, Patrick J. A year at the Met. New York: Knopf, 1983.
Straight, Michael Whitney. Twigs for an eagle's nest: government and the arts, 1965-1978. New York: Devon Press, 1979.
Stravinsky, Igor Poetics of music in the form of six lessons; New York, Vintage Books, 1959 [©1947]
Tovey, Donald Francis The forms of music. New York: Meridian Books, 1956.
Weiss, Piero Letters of composers through six centuries. Philadelphia, Chilton Book Co. [1967]
The following published recordings were removed from the collection, either to be added to the general collection, or if duplicates, offered elsewhere.
Feldman, Morton: Aki plays Feldman: 80th birthday celebration (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: Four Lakes Music, 2006
Blum, Eberhard: Anthology 1968-1998 (CD) Berlin: Eberhard Blum, 2000
Rzewski, Frederic: Antigone-Legend (1982) (LP) New York: CRI, 1987
Liszt, Franz: Arrau plays Liszt (CD) [New York]: Sony Classical, 1996
ArtMusic Ensemble: ART MUSIC ENSEMBLE Look Both Ways. (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], 1999
Los Angeles Museum of Contemporary Art: Available light (LP and booklet) Los Angeles: Museum of Contemporary Art, 1983
Neidlinger, Buell: Basso profundo music (CD) Los Angeles, CA: Vivace, 2009
Berlioz, Hector: Berlioz - Ravel - Fauré (CD) [Issy-les-Moulmeaux, France]: Virgin Classics, 2004
Rands, Bernard: Bernard Rands: Canti del sole; Canti lunatici (LP) New York: CRI, 1986
Foss, Lukas (conductor): Brooklyn Philharmonic Orchestra [playing Lou Harrison, Vladimir Ussachevsky, John Cage, Virgil Thomson, Henry Cowell, and Leo Smit] (LP) New York: Gramavision Records, 1983
CalArts Jazz Ensemble: CalArts jazz 1991 (CD) Hollywood, CA: Capitol Records, 1991
CalArts Jazz Ensemble: CalArts jazz 1993 (CD) Hollywood, CA: Capitol Records, 1993
Bach, Johann Sebastian: Cello Suites Nos. 1-6 (Casals) (1927-1939). (CD) Hong Kong: Naxos Digital Services Ltd., 2000
Eastman, Julius: Crazy nigger (DVD) Amsterdam, Netherlands: Ding Bran, 2008
Feldman, Morton: Crippled symmetry at June in Buffalo (CD) [Finland]: Frozen Reeds, 2012
Oliveros, Pauline: Crone music [concert version of Music for Lear] (CD) New York: Lovely Music, 1990
Williams, Amy: Crossings: music for piano and strings (CD) Albany, N.Y.: Albany Records, 2013
Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus: Don Giovanni [conducted by Bruno Walter] (CD) [European Union]: Andromeda, 2008
Reich, Steve: Double sextet 2 x 5 (CD) New York, NY: Nonesuch, 2010
Goode, Daniel: Eight thrushes in New York (CD) Lebanon, NH: Frog Peak Music, 2002?
Entartete Musik: Meisterwerke einer verlorenen Epoche (CD) Germany: Decca, 2005
Entremont, Philippe: Erik Satie (Cassette) New York: CBS, 1982
Ethio jazz & musique instrumentale, 1969-1974 (CD) Paris: Buda Musique, 199-
Wolff, Christian: Exercises (CD) Therwil, Switzerland: Hat, 1995
Hassell, Jon: Fascinoma (CD) Santa Barbara, CA: Water Lily Acoustics, 1999
Sahl, Michael: Funk/Romantic: music by Michael Sahl (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], undated
Hudba Ostravských Dnu live [Music of Ostrava days live] (CD) [Ostrava]: Ostravské Centrum Nové Hudby, 2009
Impulse sampler (CD) [New York]: Impulse, 1997
Riley, Terry: In C (LP) New York: Columbia, 1968
Rzewski, Frederic: Jefferson Antigone-legend (CD) New York, N.Y.: CRI, 1997
Los Angeles Guitar Quartet: Los Angeles Guitar Quartet: Praetorius, Bach, Stravinsky, Debussy, Falla (LP) Long Beach, Calif.: Orpharion, 1983
Thomas, John Patrick: Lost landscapes (CD) [United States]: J.P. Thomas, 1993
Kotik, Petr: Many many women: excerpts (LP) New York: Labor Records, 1981
Hurt, Mississippi John: Memorial anthology (CD) Silver Spring, MD: Genes CD Co., 1993
Janacek Philharmonic Orchestra: Music for 3 orchestras: Recorded live at Maerz Musik Festival Berlin, March 21, 2004 (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], 2004
Brown, Earle: Music for chamber orchestra (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: Archive Recordings, 1997
Music for instruments and computer (CD) [Cambridge, Mass.]: Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Media Laboratory, 1986?
Brown, Earle: Music for large orchestra and chamber orchestra (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: Archive recordings, 1997
Sahl, Michael: Music from 1985 (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], undated
American Brass Quintet: New American brass (CD) Tempe, Ariz.: Summit Records, 1992
Janacek Philharmonic Orchestra: Ostrava Days 2005 Festival, opening concert, August 21, 2005 (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], 2005
Tenney, James: Pika-don (CD) Suisa: Hat Hut Records :, 2005
Janacek Philharmonic Orchestra: Recorded live at Prague Spring 2005 Festival (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], 2005
La Barbara, Joan: Reluctant gypsy (LP) New York: Wizard Records, 1980
Onus (Musical group): Reoccurring dream (CD) Washington, D.C.: Hipnotic Records, 2000
Erickson, Robert: Robert Erickson (CD) New York, NY: CRI, 1991
Feldman, Morton: Rothko Chapel; For Frank O'Hara (LP) New York: Columbia/Odyssey, 1976
Cage, John: Ryoanji (CD) Therwil, Switzerland: Hat Hut Records, 1996
S.E.M. Ensemble: S.E.M. Ensemble recorded live at Paula Cooper Gallery, New York (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], 2003
Barraque, Jean: Sequence; Sonate pour piano (LP) France: Vega, 1950s
Buckner, Thomas: Sign of the times (CD) New York, NY: Lovely Music, 1994
Trythall, Richard: Solo piano (Cassette) San Francisco: Aspen Records, 1986
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix: Symphonien 3 & 4 Schottische und Italianische (CD) Hamburg: Teldec, 1988
La Barbara, Joan (singer): Tapesongs (LP) New York: Chiaroscuro Records, 1977
Reich, Steve: Tehillim Three movements (CD) New York, N.Y.: Elektra Nonesuch, 1994
Feldman, Morton: Three voices for Joan La Barbara (CD) San Francisco, Calif.: New Albion Records, 1989
Allen, Terry: Torso hell (Cassette) Los Angeles: High Performance Audio, 1987
S.E.M. Ensemble. Orchestra: Tribute to Earle Brown (CD) [Place of publication not identified]: [Publisher not identified], 2000?
Schwitters, Kurt: Ursonate (CD) Therwil, Switzerland: Hat Hut Records, 1992
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Archive of the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts
Mus. Arc. 4
Preliminary inventory of the records of the Center.